bristol.ac.uk 2011-06-02

# Bristol University | The University | Privacy and Cookie Policy

In order to operate the University of Bristol (“University”) website, we may collect and store personal information you submit to the University via this website. Please read the following privacy policy to understand how the University uses and protects the information that you provide via this website.

This system is provided and hosted by the University. By submitting your personal information, you are consenting to the University holding and using it in accordance with this policy. The policy is subject to change and any changes to it in the future will be notified on this page. By continuing to use this website you are agreeing to such changes. We recommend that you check the privacy policy each time you visit this site.

This website is known by a number of different names. These are bristol.ac.uk, bris.ac.uk, www.bristol.ac.uk, www.bris.ac.uk, bristol.edu and www.bristol.edu. This privacy policy applies to all of these, but not necessarily to others within the bristol.ac.uk, bris.ac.uk and bristol.edu domains. Please note that this website acts as a transparent proxy to some other University of Bristol websites which may be subject to their own privacy policies. A list of these is available at <http://www.bristol.ac.uk/university/web/outside-pp.html>.

## Contents

  1. [Information that we collect from you and your use of this website](http://www.bristol.ac.uk/university/web/privacy-policy.html#info-coll)
  2. [How we use your information](http://www.bristol.ac.uk/university/web/privacy-policy.html#use-info)
  3. [How we handle the data submitted by you](http://www.bristol.ac.uk/university/web/privacy-policy.html#handle-data)
  4. [Links to external web sites](http://www.bristol.ac.uk/university/web/privacy-policy.html#ext-web)
  5. [How to contact us](http://www.bristol.ac.uk/university/web/privacy-policy.html#how-cont)

## 1\. Information that we collect from you and your use of this website

### 1.1 Information you give us

When you visit this website you may be asked to provide certain information about yourself, including your name and contact details. 

### 1.2 Automatic Information

We automatically receive and save certain types of information whenever you interact with this website. We use the information to monitor website traffic and to assist with the navigation and user experience of the website.

Information that we will automatically receive includes:

  * Requested URL (Uniform Resource Locator)
  * IP (Internet Protocol) address (this may or may not identify a specific computer)
  * Domain name from which you access the internet
  * Referring URL
  * Software (browser/operating system) used to access the page
  * Date and time pages were visited

When you visit some pages on this website, your computer may be issued with a small file - a “cookie”. A cookie is a piece of information in the form of a very small text file that is placed on the hard drive of your computer. The information the cookie contains is set by the server (this website) and it can be used by that server whenever you visit this website. The server uses cookies to recognise your browser session if you visit multiple pages during your interaction with this website.

You can set your browser to refuse cookies or warn you before accepting them. However, some parts of this website may not function properly without accepting cookies.

Some parts of this website use Google Analytics ([see Section 2 below](http://www.bristol.ac.uk/university/web/privacy-policy.html#use-info)) which also place cookies on your computer. The information generated by these cookies about your use of this website will be transmitted to and stored by Google, For further information about cookies, please see [AboutCookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/).

Flash Cookies (or Local Shared Objects) can be used by websites to collect information about a user’s browsing habits even though the user believes that they have restricted such data collection. The use of Flash Cookies is not permitted on University websites. 

## 2\. How we use your information

We may use and analyse the information we collect so that we can manage and improve the services on the website. Demographic and statistical information about user behaviour may be collected and used to analyse the popularity and effectiveness of the website. Any disclosure of this information will be in aggregate form and will not identify individual users.

The University of Bristol also uses services from Google and Nedstat on this website to measure and analyse visitor information. For further information on these, please visit [Nedstat’s website](http://www.nedstat.com/) and [Google’s website](http://www.google.com/analytics/).

The University will not (nor will it allow any third party to) use the statistical analytics tools to track or to collect personally identifiable information of visitors to this website. The University will not associate any data gathered with any personally identifying information from any source as part of our use of the statistical analytics tools.

## 3\. How we handle the data submitted by you

### 3.1 Data Protection Legislation

The University is your data controller. As your data controller the University has notified its activities to the Office of the Information Commissioner as required under the Data Protection Act 1998 (the “Act”) and is listed in the Public Register of Data Controllers. Personal information will only be collected and/or processed by the University in accordance with the Act.

### 3.2 Disclosure of your information

  * Except as set out in this policy or as required by law, your personal data will not be provided to any third party without your prior written consent
  * The information you provide to us will be held on our computers in the UK. It may be accessed by or given to third parties some of whom may be located outside the European Economic Area who act for us for the purposes set out in this policy or for other purposes approved by you. Those parties process information and may provide support services to the University or on the University’s behalf. 
  * Countries outside the European Economic Area do not always have strong data protection laws. However, we will always take steps to ensure that your information is used by third parties in accordance with this policy.

### 3.3 Monitoring Use of University Systems

In order to protect the security and working of University network and computer systems, it may be necessary to monitor or log the use of these systems. If there are indications of abuse of systems or that individuals may be using systems in excess of their authority, files, messages and any or all uses of the systems may be intercepted, monitored, recorded, copied, audited, inspected and disclosed to authorised University and law enforcement personnel.

## 4\. Links to external websites

This website may contain links to other websites that are outside the University’s control and are not covered by this privacy policy.

## 5\. How to contact us

Should the information we hold about you be incorrect, you can change and update your personal information and you can have your information corrected by contacting us.

Where requested, we will provide you with a readable copy of the personal data which we keep about you, by contacting us at the address below. We may require proof of your identity before supplying you with this information to ensure confidentiality. We are entitled by law to charge a fee of £10 to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you.

We allow you to challenge the data we hold about you and where appropriate you may have the data erased, rectified, amended or completed. For complaints or queries about the privacy policy or data protection queries generally please contact:

**Information Rights Manager**  
University of Bristol  
Senate House  
Tyndall Avenue  
Bristol  
BS8 1TH, UK

Email: [data-protection@bristol.ac.uk](mailto:data-protection@bristol.ac.uk)

May 2008 – University of Bristol
